Guide to the Publius Virgilius Rogers papers,1843-1918.
Rogers, Publius Virgilius papers, 1843-1918.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publius Virgilius Rogers papers, 1843-1918.
821
Publius Virgilius Rogers.
9.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, accounts, mortgages, notes, articles, papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, accounts, mortgages, notes, articles, and other papers largely relating to Rogers' interests in banking affairs, the industrial development of central New York, and land and railroad investments; also, letters and papers concerning his son and family.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lawyer and bank president in Utica, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, accounts, mortgages, notes, articles, and other papers largely relating to Rogers' interests in banking affairs, the industrial development of central New York, and land and railroad investments. Includes letters and papers of Rogers' son, Charles Butler Rogers, and material relating to the Central Railroad of Iowa, the Flint & Pere Marquette Railroad, Hamilton College, the Iowa Valley Construction Company, the Oswego River Starch Company, the Patent Cereals Company of Geneva, New York, the Remington Armory at Ilion, New York, the Utica Steam Cotton Mills, and the Utica Steam Woolen Mills. Other topics include merchandizing, dairy farming, travel description, gold mining in Colorado, student life in Germany at the Koniglichen Friedrich-Willelms Universitat, hospitals, charitable institutions, and art; Correspondents include Isaac M. Cate, William W. Crapo, William H. Ferry, George S. Goodale, H. C. Potter, JohnH. Prentiss, F. W. H. Sheffield, Breese Stevens, and Anson J. Upson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rogers, Publius Virgilius.; Rogers, Publius Virgilius.; Cate, Isaac M.; Crapo, William W.; Ferry, William H.; Goodale, George S.; Potter, H. C.; Prentiss, F. W. H.; Rogers, Charles Butler.; Stevens, Breese.; Upson, Anson J.; Central Railroad of Iowa.; Flint & Pere Marquette Railroad.; Hamilton College.; Iowa Valley Construction Company.; Friedrich-Wilhelms Universitat Berlin.; Oswego River Starch Company.; Patent Cereals Company.; Remington Armory (Ilion, N.Y.); Utica Steam Cotton Mills (N.Y.); Utica Steam Woolen Mills (N.Y.)
Subjects:
Banks and banking--New York (State)--Utica.; Real property--New York (State); Industrialization--New York (State); Railroads--Iowa.; Railroads--Michigan.; Dairy farming--New York (State); Gold mines and mining--Colorado.; Hospitals.; Universities and colleges--Germany.; Charities.; Lawyers--New York (State)--Utica.
Places:
Nebraska--Description and travel.; Oneida County (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Pamphlets
Boxes 1-4, 26
Series II. Volumes, Ledgers, and Books
Boxes 4-6, 25-27
Series III. Correspondence
Boxes 7-22, 26
Series IV. Miscellaneous
Boxes 6, 23-24, 26
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Pamphlets
  - Historical Discourse, Delivered at the Whitestone Centennial Celebration, by Charles Tracy, June 5, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Handbook of the New-Public Library in Boston, Compiled by Herbert Small (Box 1)
  - St. Luke's Home, Opening Services, Addresses, Extracts from The Sermon of R. Rev. F.D. Huntington, D.D., 1870 (Box 1)
  - Hand-Book on Mormonism, 1882 (Box 1)
  - The Utica Orphan Asylum, 1874-1875 (Box 1)
  - An Appeal for the Equipment of the Soldier's Field (Harvard) (Box 1)
  - Ordnung des Umganges (Box 1)
  - W.L. Townsend, Ye Olde Booke Shopps, Catalogue (Box 1)
  - Leben in Thiergeftalt (Box 1)
  - Body and Mind; Their Conservative Influence on Each Other, by Mrs. Clemence S. Lozier, M.D., Professor in the New York Medical College for Women, August 2-4, 1870 (Box 1)
  - Health Tract. #3, DRESS, by DR. Clemence S. Lozier, 1874 (Box 1)
  - Cornell University Announcement of Courses of Instruction for Graduate Undergraduate Students for the Academic Year. With Rules for the Guidance of Students and Revised Courses of Study, 1891-1892 (Box 1)
  - St. Luke's Hospital, Training School for Nurses in the City of Utica, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly Publications of the American Statistical Association, 1901 (Box 1)
  - The Water Works Question: Viewed by a citizen who has the welfare of Kansas City at heart, and a mortgage on his home; by T.R. Tinsley, 1891 (Box 1)
  - Annual Circular and Catalogue of the Utica Female Academy., 1847-1848 (Box 1)
  - Catalogue Des Tresours De Mycenes au Musee D'Athenes, 1882 (Box 1)
  - Hand-Book of the American Economic Association 1896, together with Report of the Eighth Annual Meeting, April 1896 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton College, Report of Finance Committee, from Apr. 1, 1850-July 1, 1876, with a Comparative Statement showing the condition of the property and finances of the college, December 30, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Value, Price and Distribution by Charles William MacFarlane, Ph.D.; An Historical, Critical, and Constructive Study in Economic Theory Adapted for advanced and Post-Graduate Work (Box 1)
  - Report of the Secretary of the Treasury on the State of the Finances for the Year, 1868 (Box 1)
  - Loan Exhibition for the Benefit of St. Luke's Home and Hospital, including the Mathews Collection of Paintings, and many Modern Works of Art, Utica, N.Y., February 1887 (Box 1)
  - The Sigma Phi Club, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Les Marbres du Museecentral, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Catalogue of the Sigma Phi, E.P.V. with the Thesaurus, 1880 (Box 1)
  - English-German Dictionary (Box 1)
  - Standing Committees, with Extract from the minutes of the Board of Trustees of Hamilton College (Box 1)
  - To the Bondholders of the Central Railroad Company of Iowa, July 15, 1847 (Box 1)
  - The Central Railroad Co. of Iowa, Compromise Measure, June 1875 (Box 1)
  - Harvard College, Class of 1888, Baccalaureate Hymn, Class Day Oration, Class Day Poem, Class Day Ode, Class Day Song (Box 1)
  - American Economic Association, Economic Studies; Government by Injunction, by William H. Dunbar, A.M., L.L.B., February 1898 (Box 1)
  - A Complete Handbook to the National Museum in Naples according to Its New Arrangement, 1875 (Box 1)
  - Harvard, Class Dinner, December 2, 1887, 1888 (Box 1)
  - A List of Fine Works on Medieval Costumes, Illuminated Ornaments, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Seventy-Sixth Commencement of Hamilton College, 1888 (Box 1)
  - First Annual Report of the Women's Christian Association of Utica, N.Y., June 1871 (Box 1)
  - Utica Academy, Annual Exercises, Class of 1882, June 29, 1882 (Box 1)
  - Investors' Supplement of the Commercial and Financial Chronicle, January 27, 1894 (Box 1)
  - Extra Census Bulletin, January 24, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Description of the Lawrence Scientific School of Harvard University, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Deutfche Litteratur and Philologic an ber, Harvard Univerfitat, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Harvard University, Faculty of Arts and Sciences. Announcement of Courses for Teachers on Methods of Instruction (Box 1)
  - Student's Expenses. A Collection of letters from Undergraduates, Graduates, and Professional School Students describing in Detail Their Necessary Expenses at Harvard University with an Introduction by Frank Bolles, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Country Banking, 1861 (Box 2)
  - The Finance Minister, The Currency, and The Public Debt, by Henry C. Carey from the North American U.S. Gazette, 1868 (Box 2)
  - French Grammar (Box 2)
  - Announcement of Summer Courses of Instruction, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Harvard University, Seminar of American History, 1891-1892 (Box 2)
  - Harvard University, Rank-Lists, 1887-1888 (Box 2)
  - Harvard University, Class of 1888, Secretary's Report No. 1, 1889 (Box 2)
  - The Folsom-Cook Exploration of the Upper Yellowstone in the Year 1869, by David E. Folsom with a preface by Nathaniel P. Langford, 1894 (Box 2)
  - National Academy of Design, Loan Exhibition, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Catalogue, Eighth Annual Exhibition of Paintings, 1882 (Box 2)
  - Revised Edition, Official Catalogue of Exhibits, Descriptive Catalogue, World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Theatre National De L'Opera Comique (Box 2)
  - Harvard University, Account of the Graduate Department, 1888-1889 (Box 2)
  - Harvard University, The Divinity School (Box 2)
  - Scriber's Magazine, February 1895 (Box 2)
  - "A Remarkable Work by a Remarkable Man," The Life of Our Lord Jesus Christ, by Mons. J. James Tissot, 1900 (Box 2)
  - Antique Glass, from Greece, Asia Minor, Egypt, and Cyprus, 1895 (Box 2)
  - American Water Color Society, Catalogue of the Twelfth Annual Exhibition, 1879 (Box 2)
  - Address of Horatio Seymour at the Dairymen's International Exhibition, New York, December 1878 (Box 2)
  - Sound Currency, New York, December 1899 (Box 2)
  - State of New York, No. 470, In Senate, February 14, 1898 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Circuit Court, District of Iowa, The Farmer's Loan and Trust Co. against The Central Railroad Company of Iowa, and others., 1876 (Box 2)
  - Sound Currency, New York, February 1900 (Box 2)
  - Sound Currency, New York, November 1899 (Box 2)
  - Sound Currency, New York, April 1900 (Box 2)
  - Sixty-Sixth Commencement of Hamilton College, 1878 (Box 2)
  - Statement to the Bondholders of the Holly, Wayne, and Monroe Railroad, and of the Flint and Pere Marquette Railway Company, Land Grants (Box 2)
  - Office of Flint and Pere Marquette Railway Co., February 1876 (Box 2)
  - Flint and Pere Railway Co., Statement to Bondholders (Box 2)
  - The Canadian Pacific (Box 2)
  - Ancestors, The Roll of Honor, Volume 1 (Box 2)
  - 1870-1880, A Sermon preached at the close of his ministry in The Second Presbyterian Church, Albany, N.Y., by the Rev. Anson J, Upson, D.D., L.L.D., July 11, 1880 (Box 2)
  - St. Luke's Home, Hospital and Mission, Reports for 1870-1871 with Charter, Constitution, By-Laws, and Officers, December 15, 1869 (Box 2)
  - Health Tract, No.2, Care of Children by Clemence S. Loizer, 1871 (Box 2)
  - St. Luke's Home and Hospital in the City of Utica, 1886 (Box 2)
  - Loan Exhibition for the Benefit of St. Luke's Home and Hospital, including the Mathews Collection of Paintings and many Modern Works of Art, February 1887 (Box 2)
  - A Catalogue of a few Recent Purchases, and Announcements of New Publications, by Bernard Quaritch, 15 Piccadilly, November 1890 (Box 2)
  - A Sermon, preached at the funeral of Miss Henrietta Butler, in the Union Church, Sauquoit, N.Y., by Rev. John Waugh, February 2, 1842 (Box 2)
  - Rules and Regulations of Forest Hill Company (Box 2)
  - Malpewood Young Ladies' Institute, Pittsfield, Massachusetts, 1865-1866 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report of the Flint and Pere Marquette Railway Company of Michigan, December 31, 1878 (Box 2)
  - Letter and Authentic Documentary Evidence in relation to the Trinity Church Property, in the City of New York, submitted to the Commissioners of the Land Office, by Rutger B. Miller, June 21, 1855 (Box 2)
  - A Sermon preached at the funeral of Miss Henrietta Butler, in the Union Church, Sauquoit, N.Y., by Rev. John Waugh, February 2, 1842 (Box 2)
  - The Magazine Art, November 1890 (Box 2)
  - Health Tract, Care of Children by Dr. Clemence S. Lozier #2, 1871 (Box 2)
  - National Academy of Design, Catalogue of the Forty-Ninth Annual Exhibition, 1874 (Box 2)
  - State of Michigan, Report of H.C. Potter, Receiver, January 12, 1881 (Box 2)
  - Loan Exhibition in aid of the Society of Decorative Art, 1878 (Box 2)
  - Annual Address before the Medical Society of the State of N.Y., by Jihn P. Gray, M.D., Feb.ruary 5, 1868 (Box 2)
  - Third Annual Report of the Women's Christian Association of Utica, N.Y., June 1873 (Box 2)
  - Portraits by Otto Ritter Von Krumhaar, February 9-23, 1903 (Box 2)
  - Ye Hastie Puddynge Clubbe (Box 2)
  - The Beginning of the "Spoils" System in the National Government, 1829-1830 (Box 2)
  - Fetes de Jeunes Filles, Scenes at Dialogues par L'Auteur des Festes D'Enfants Paris, 1876 (Box 2)
  - Scriber's Monthly Illustrated Magazine, November 1880 (Box 2)
  - National Academy of Design, Catalogue of the Forty-Sixth Annual Exhibition, 1871 (Box 2)
  - AMERICAN Art Galleries, Special Exhibition (Box 2)
  - Theatre D'Athenee (Box 2)
  - Catalogue of the Loan Exhibition, in aid of Faxton Hospital and Home for Aged Men, 1879 (Box 2)
  - Comedie Francaise (Box 2)
  - State of New York, Commission in Lunacy, January 2, 1898 (Box 2)
  - Peter Henderson and Co., Manual of Everything for the Garden, 1898 (Box 2)
  - The Chronicle, Commercial and Financial, Hunt's Merchant's Magazine, February 25, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Supreme Court of the United States, Opinion of associate Justice Miller upon application to vacate appeal bond (Box 3)
  - Document No. 4 to the First Mortgage Bondholders of the Central R.R. Co., of Iowa (Box 3)
  - Report of L.M. Fisher, Special Master (Box 3)
  - Loan Exhibition, St. Luke's Home and Hospital (Box 3)
  - Comedie Francaise (Box 3)
  - National Academy of Design, Catalogue of the Fifty-Third Annual Exhibition, 1878 (Box 3)
  - Theatre National De L'Opera, programme (Box 3)
  - Minutes of the Council of the National Society of the Colonial Dames of America held in Washington D.C., April 1896 (Box 3)
  - Cornell Reading-Course for Farmers' Wives, Home Sanitation (Box 3)
  - Sixty-Sixth Commencement of Hamilton College, 1878 (Box 3)
  - Standing Committees, with Extract from the minutes of the Board of Trustees, of Hamilton College (Box 3)
  - Supreme Court of the United States, appeal from the Circuit Court of the United States for the Southern District of Alabama (Box 3)
  - Document No. Six, Central Railroad of Iowa, to the First Mortgage Bondholders, New York, September 7, 1877 (Box 3)
  - Abstract of Articles of Incorporation of the Iowa Central Railway Co. (Box 3)
  - The Central Railroad Co. of Iowa, Compromise Measure, September 1877 (Box 3)
  - Official Catalogue of Exhibits, Fine Arts, 1893 (Box 3)
  - Portraits of Women Loan Exhibition, November 1894 (Box 3)
  - Handbook of the Pompeia, A Grand Roman House (Box 3)
  - Old Chinese Porcelains, Jades, Agates, Amethysts, etc., Fifth Avenue Art Galleries (Box 3)
  - National Academy of Design, Sixty-Sixth Annual Exhibition (Box 3)
  - Loan Exhibition of Paintings, April 1895 (Box 3)
  - The Colonial Dames of the State of New York, Incorporated, 1893 (Box 3)
  - Munchener Kalen der fur, 1889 (Box 3)
  - "The Lord's Supper" painted by P.A.J. Dagnan-Bouveret, Descriptive Note by Rev. F.W. Farrar (Box 3)
  - Catalogue illustre du Salon de 1899, 1899 (Box 3)
  - Catalogue of a collection of thirty-one Water-Color Drawings, 1895 (Box 3)
  - Regulations and Law relative to Income tax, December 13, 1894 (Box 3)
  - Mademoiselle de La Seigliere, Comedie, 1887 (Box 3)
  - To the National President and the Members of the National and Executive Committees on the Spanish War Memorial (Box 3)
  - National Academy of Design, New York Centennial Loan Exhibition, 1876 (Box 3)
  - National Academy of Design, Catalogue of the Fiftieth Annual Exhibition, 1875 (Box 3)
  - Main Picture Gallery Telfair Academy of Arts and Sciences, Savannah, Ga., 1891 (Box 3)
  - Catalogue of the Loan Exhibition of Paintings at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, March 1874 (Box 3)
  - Exhibition of Books and Manuscripts, by Bernard Quaritch, January 27, 1890 (Box 3)
  - Ellis and Elvey's Catalogue of Recent Purchases of Rare, Curious, and Interesting Books (Box 3)
  - Reports and Organization of Faxton Hospital and Home for Aged Men, 1886 (Box 3)
  - The Utica Orphan Asylum, 1880 (Box 3)
  - The Doom of Slavery in the Union, It's Safety, 1860 (Box 3)
  - THE CALL TO WORK, A Baccalaureate Sermon to the Senior Class of the University of North Carolina, by the Rev. Charles H. Hall, D.D., June 2, 1886 (Box 3)
  - Thirty-Third Annual Report of the Children's Aid Society, November 1885 (Box 3)
  - St. Luke's Home and Hospital in the City of Utica, 1889 (Box 3)
  - In the Supreme Court, The People on rel. the Black River Bank, 1853 (Box 3)
  - The Tariff Supplement to the Commercial and Financial Chronicle, July 31, 1897 (Box 3)
  - Aunt Roger's Legacy (Box 3)
  - Sound Currency, July 15, 1897 (Box 3)
  - Sound Currency, August 1, 1897 (Box 3)
  - The Canal Railway, Argument of Hon. W.W. Astor, March 9, 1881 (Box 3)
  - The Farmer's Loan and Trust Company vs. The Central Railroad Company of Iowa (Box 3)
  - In the matter of the People's Safe Deposit and Savings Institution of The State of New York, a Bankrupt (Box 3)
  - Brief and Points for the Plaintiffs in Error, G. Clarence Churchill et al., vs. The City of Utica (Box 3)
  - The First Four Voyages of Amerigo Vespucci, Reproduced in Facsimile with Translation, Introduction, A Map, and a Facsimile of a Drawing by Stradanus, 1893 (Box 3)
  - The Spanish Letter of Columbus, written by him on Feb. 15, 1493, to announce the discovery of America, 1893 (Box 3)
  - Saving Steps, Cornell Reading Course for Farmer's Wives (Box 3)
  - Tristan und Isolde, 1882 (Box 3)
  - Catalogue of Imported Books, mainly in elegant bindings including Finely Illustrated and Rare Books (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Catalogues (Box 3)
  - Labour and the Hours of Labor, by William Mather, M.P., 1892 (Box 3)
  - With the Compliments and Good Wishes of the Season, Morning Herald (Box 3)
  - The Influence of New York on American Jurisprudence, by Horatio Seymour (Box 3)
  - Prospectus of the Baltimore and Drum Point Railroad Co. for the Sale of Its First Mortgage Bonds, payable in gold, 1882 (Box 3)
  - Security Loan and Trust Company, Debentures (Box 3)
  - Mr. Russell Sage, Vice President Central Iowa Railway Co., printed letter (Box 3)
  - Argument of Herbert B. Turner, Esq., The Farmer's Loan and Trust Co. against The Central Railway Company of Iowa, et al. (Box 3)
  - Central Iowa Railway Company, Report, 1882 (Box 3)
  - Printed Indenture (Box 3)
  - New York State Department of Agriculture (Box 3)
  - Brief of Platt Smith for Charles Alexander, et al. vs. Central Railroad of Iowa, et al. (Box 3)
  - W.E. Fan Motors, Alternating Current Ceiling Fans, 1903 (Box 3)
  - Historical Incidents relating to the Whitesboro Cemetery, 1879 (Box 3)
  - Fiananzwissenschaft, von Adolph Wagner (Box 3)
  - To Oppose the Silver Bill (Box 3)
  - Opinion of Chief Justice Chase and of Associate Justice Wayne and Swayne in the Supreme Court of the United States, December Term, 1865 (Box 3)
  - The People, on the relation of William B. Storm vs. The Superintendent of the Bank Department of the State of New York, Opinion of Hon. Philo Gridley, 1853 (Box 3)
  - The Savings Bank Association: Origin of the Plan, July 24, 1878 (Box 3)
  - Thomas Walker, Pres. of the Bank of Utica vs. Chauncey Crain, Appellant's Points and Judge Allen's Opinion, 1853 (Box 4)
  - Thomas Walker, President of the Bank of Utica vs. Chauncy Crain Case on Appeal, 1853 (Box 4)
  - A Guide Book for Visitors to Japan, 1893 (Box 4)
  - Harper's Franklin Suare Library, Ancient American Politics by Hugh J. Hastings (Box 4)
  - Report of the Committee appointed to inquire into the Indian Currency, 1899 (Box 4)
  - The Cronomist, Weekly Commercial Times, Dec. 16, 1899 (Box 4)
  - 20th Century Toilet Hints (Box 4)
  - Specimen Cooper-Plate Portraits from American Illustrated, compiled by W. Dunbar (Box 4)
  - Report of Tax Committees of the N.Y. Boston and Phila, Clearing House Associations, 1863 (Box 4)
  - Studies of Some Shade Tree and Timber Destroying Fungi, by Geo. F. Atkins; Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, 1901 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the Secretary of the Treasury on the State of the Finances for the Year 1877, 1877 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the Treasurer of the United States, 1876 (Box 4)
  - Report of the Superintendent of the Banking Department relative to Savings Banks, February 19, 1858 (Box 4)
  - Treasury Notes a Legal Tender; Argument of John K. Porter, The Metro. Bank et al. vs. Henry H. Van Syck, Superin. of the Bank Department, June 27, 1863 (Box 4)
  - Short Road to Specie, Sample (Box 4)
  - A Series of Letters, written for the Roman Citizen on the Currency and Public Debt of the United States by John B. Jervis, 1868 (Box 4)
  - Convention of National Banks, October 19, 1864 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Peach-tree Borer, 1901 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Dwarf Apples (Box 4)
  - Experimental Studies in Higher Education, A Summer School of Art and Science, 1891 (Box 4)
  - Tenth Annual Report of the Homestead Aid Association of Utica, December 18, 1893 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, The Texture of Soil, by L.H. Bailey, 1896 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Tillage Experiments with Potatoes, by J.L. Stone, 1901 (Box 4)
  - North German Lloyd, Mediterranean Station, 1903 (Box 4)
  - Prices on a Gold Basis, by Gen. A.J. Warner, January 12, 1894 (Box 4)
  - Sound Currency, Feb. 1, 1897 (Box 4)
  - North German Lloyd, Rates of First Cabin Passage, 1903 (Box 4)
  - Cornell Reading-Course for Farmer's Wives, Saving Strength (Box 4)
  - A Bill, March 10, 1902 (Box 4)
  - The Control of Trusts, An argument in favor of curbing the power of monopoly by the natural method, by John Bates Clark (Box 4)
  - TO OUR PATRONS AND THE PUBLIC (Box 4)
  - Colonial Dames of the State of New York, prize Historical Essay, June 1896 (Box 4)
  - Health Tract, Care of Children, by Dr. Clemence S. Lozier, 1871 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of the Sixth Exhibition of Paintings, Utica, 1878 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of paintings on exhibition by the Utica Art Association, 1878 (Box 4)
  - Board of Trustees of the Utica Art Association for 1882, 1882 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of Paintings and Sculpture, Utica Art Association, 1868 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of Paintings and Sculpture, Utica Art Association, 1871 (Box 4)
  - Catalogue of the Eighth Exhibition of Paintings, Utica Art Association, 1882 (Box 4)
  - Harvard College, Topics and References in Political Economy IV, 1885 (Box 4)
  - The Treasury Investigation, The Suppressed Documents; Report on the printing of the public money (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, Some Tent-Markers, by Anna Botsford Comstock (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, A Children's Garden, by L.H. Bailey (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, The Life History of the Toad, by Simon Henry Gage (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, Hints on Making Collections of Insects, by Anna Botsford Comstock (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets on Nature-Study No. 11 (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, How A Candle Burns, by George W. Cavanaugh (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, Hints on Making Collections of Insects, by Anna Botsford Comstock (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets; The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, What is Nature-Study? by L.H. Bailey (Box 4)
  - Farmer's Reading Lessons, The College of Agriculture, Cornell University, Texture of Soil and Conservation of Moisture, by Jno. W. Spencer, Conductor (Box 4)
  - Report of the Comptroller of the Currency, November 28, 1863 (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets on Nature-Study, No. 3 (Box 4)
  - Teacher's Leaflets, College of Agriculture, Cornell University, How A Squash Plant Gets Out of the Seed, by L.H. Bailey (Box 4)
  - Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, The Moisture of Soil and Its Conservation, by L.A. Clinton, 1897 (Box 4)
  - Report of the National Bank Currency Act, its defects and its effects, 1863 (Box 4)
  - National Society of the Colonial Dames of America, List of Members of the Colonial Dames of the State of New York (Box 4)
  - Constitution and Eligibility Lists of the National Society of the Colonial Dames of America (Box 4)